Hey, we get a point. Programming can be very fun and useful if you do it the right way,
but a lot of people end up quitting their leak as they start off like this.
Also use a negative index.
So let me teach you the fun way to learn programming. I'd say that the best starting point for
everybody would be Python and then after that you can specialize on whatever you want.
Just look a Python tutorial on YouTube or find a website and pick whichever one is least
annoying to you because they all pretty much teach you the same thing. For now I'll
learn basic syntax and basic programming. If you want to do it properly, don't just
blindly follow whatever they do in the tutorial. You need to do three very important things.
Experiment with the code and understand what you're actually writing. Make your own small
projects that you actually enjoy working on and make sure that the way you're doing
it is the best way to do it before you move forward.
First you're going to need something to write your code in. I would recommend VS Code.
I'm not going to show you how to set that up because you don't have the attention span
and it's easy anyway. And I will show you how to follow the first rule. During this video,
I'm focusing on the code itself, just the general methods that I'm explaining. So let's
say I'm watching a tutorial and the YouTuber tells me that the function input takes
user input and then I can use it however I want. In the example he takes age as an input
and then prints out this is your age. Pretty simple, but then the YouTuber moves on.
You might not really understand what the function does if you stop there. So you might want
to experiment. Here's how you do it. First I take the function and then I try to print
it out. I can see that if I press enter and I don't input anything, I don't get any
output. But if I type something in, I get that exact same thing printed out. So basically
whatever I type goes inside of input. Now this part is starting to make a bit more sense.
Whatever I type into input gets put into age and then age gets printed. But then that
also tells me that I don't need the age variable. I can just put the input straight inside
of the print. Another interesting feature is that it stalls all of my code until I get
rid of the input by pressing enter. So basically this code down here will only execute if I
press enter. So then we have Larry. He was building his temple, but he couldn't really
see very well. So he couldn't put the star on top of the temple. I need to find the
exact coordinates to tell him where to put the star or it's just gonna fall off and he's
gonna be very sad. I'll use Win32 API to get my cursor position, but if I run it normally
it's just gonna tell me where my cursor is when I'm on my VS code. This doesn't help Larry
in any way. But then I remember I can just told the code with input. I can move my mouse
on top of where he needs to put the star and then I can get him the coordinates by just
pressing enter because it makes my code run. Look at how happy Larry is now. Obviously
it doesn't the best way to stall code, but I was just showing you how to explore something
new. So now that I experimented with the function
a bit I understand it better. Now I want to personalize it and make a small project out
of it because this one is very basic. I don't feel like making a whole project out of it.
So I'm just gonna customize it for now. In my case I'm just gonna use YouTubers instead
of age. And now the last step is to make sure that I do it properly. Throughout this video
I've been printing out strings wrong because this is usually how beginners learn them by
just adding strings together. The way you're actually supposed to do it is by using string
formatting and that would look something like this, which leads me to the next point.
How do you know how to do it properly? Well honestly just use AI. AI is basically just a
personal teacher for you that's there to guide you throughout everything. Anyone that
tells you that AI is bad for learning in this context is objectively wrong. Yes it is
bad to heavily rely on AI and make it make entire projects for you and not learn anything
obviously. But if you're just giving it a few errors, if you're making it explain to
you why your code doesn't work or if there's a better way to do it, it's an incredibly
valuable tool and I think everyone should be using it. Now let me give you a bit of a
better example for the second rule. Let's take an array. An array is just kind of a list
of items that all have a certain slot and then you can just find the item by the slot,
usually in tutorials to use fruit or names as examples. But let's make this more fun
and personal. Let's say I want to play Valorant and I want my script to decide a random
character for me to play. Well I can just fill out an array with every character name
and instead of doing it manually I can just save some time and tell you a GPT to make
me the array. So now if I ask for the agent that index 2 it's gonna look 0, 1, 2 and it
should be common. There it is. Now how do I randomize it? Well I need to find some sort
of a random number generator so I'm gonna look up how to generate a random number in Python.
I found out that I can use the random module. Now I'm gonna make it generate a random
number between 1 and 27. In this case between 0 and 26 cause arrays started 0 and then
it's just gonna print out the character at that position in the array pretty much picking
me a random character. I think that's a pretty cool project and also in the process I learned
how arrays work better and I learned how to generate random numbers and throughout time
you're gonna learn a lot of different stuff by doing these sorts of small projects and
the more complex the project the more you're gonna learn. Learning the basics should only
take you a few days to a week so it shouldn't be that bad and then after that you get to
start having fun cause you can do whatever project you want. I didn't only tell you
to start with Python because it's the easiest to learn but also it's extremely versatile
so you can do pretty much anything with it. It's also gonna help you allat in the future
whenever you wanna make a custom tool that doesn't exist or you wanna automate some tasks
because it's so easy to do with Python. When it comes to languages people worry about
this way too much in the beginning it really doesn't matter. The most important thing
is that you learn to program properly and then you can hop between languages very easily.
Once you learn to program it's easy to learn a new language and it's a lot faster than
learning your first language. In fact developers pick up new languages all the time if it's
the most suitable for the project that they're working on except me I'm not touching Java
and now let's talk about cool projects. Until now we pretty much just dealt with strings
and static values in the code we didn't really get external information like we didn't
interact with any apps or websites or anything interesting. Now it's time to spice it up
and interact with external platforms. There's three main ways to do this.
Let's see you're playing an online multiplayer game and you have matches with other players.
The game provider tracks those games and keeps them stored on a database. The company's
not gonna give you direct access to their database for obvious reasons but they are gonna
provide an API that lets you interact with it. This means that you can pull and manipulate
whatever relevant information you want in your program. This can be done with many services
not just games but I'm gonna use Ligas an example for now. In this case I'm gonna make
an account and get an API key that allows me to interact with API. First I'm gonna
get the player identifier by giving it the in-game tag. Afterwards I can look for the player's
match history data with the PUI data I just got. Then I can get the match data by the
match ID that I just pulled from the match history and now I have all of the match data
for that game. The API looks something like this but then I can take specific values
and modify it with some front end to make it look like this and there's a lot of sites
that do this for many different games. Like here we can see the level, the champion, the
number of deaths and a bunch of things that don't even show up like how many times they
pinged. You can do all of this in Python through request by the way. Now let's do something
a bit more entertaining. I'm gonna take a live game and I'm gonna use the game API to
get me the in-game data. So this is what the API looks like and it gets me stats like
my character stats, for example my attack damage, my HP, my attack speed and other stuff.
I can pull all of those stats through their API and manipulate it however I wanted my script.
In my case I'm just gonna print it out in the terminal and now we can see that as my
attack speed gets higher in game it also updates in the terminal. This means that my script
currently has active live game data. With this I could do something like a Discord presence
bot which shows my KDA and my farming real time as I'm playing a game so that people on
Discord can see that. Or I could go the evil route and just make a kiting script out of
it, although I can't really show you that on YouTube. There's APIs for all sorts of platforms,
it doesn't have to be league or any game for that matter so if you don't really care about games,
you can do it for whatever your interest are. Let's say that you like football, you can just find
an API that gets you player data or match data and then make an app that displays it or indexes it.
You can also do it externally by scanning the screen or having preset positions and then
simulating user input like your mouse and keyboard actions. This is harder to detect by antichutes and
it's also useful for quick automation. Here you have to wait for it to turn green and then
click it and check your reaction time. First I'm gonna make it check a pixel from somewhere around here.
If it turns green it's gonna have this RGB value so I can just put it in a loop and constantly
scan that pixel to see if it reaches that value. If it does I just make it click by simulating my mouse
input. This way I only use screen detection and keyboard and mouse manipulation so I don't actually
inject into the browser or do any sorts of site requests. It's called a pixel scanner and I do it
externally. This was a simple example but there's much more interesting examples like this one where
I just automate an entire game by using the same technique. Pretty much everything that's actively
running in a program is stored in memory. This means that if I were to find the memory address
from a hb I could change that however I want. This has limitations because of antichutes and other
stuff but that's the general concept of internals. Basically if you're injecting into a process and
you're editing or reading its memory directly you're doing internals. These are general used for
game cheats. If you're interested in that I'm gonna have a kernel level antichute documentary
coming up next month. I also documented some of my Python projects. Earlier I told you to use
chatchipity for help but now the projects are getting far too advanced where it to be able to
properly help you. Trying to do this through an lm chat just simply doesn't work at this scale.
It wasn't built for that. Luckily today's sponsor came in clutch. MeetWarp2.0 an
agentic development environment where agents actually do the heavy lifting across the entire
development lifecycle. It's a top performer on terminal bench above cloud code and Gemini CLI
and scored 71% on SWE bench verified making it one of the highest performing coding agents out
there. Warp isn't just another chat window or autocomplete toy. It's built at the right level in the
stack. It picks the best model for the job or less you choose the best model. Gathers context
across repos, plans, summarizes and then applies fixes directly to files. You can run multiple
agents in parallel, manage their autonomy from a clear UI, edit the diffs in app and then commit
and push without using 20 different apps and a lm chat interfaces. The whole workflow is literally
what Warp2.0 is made for. There's a reason why over 600,000 engineers use Warp. The best part is
that they have a free plan and you can easily try it yourself without having to buy anything.
If you enjoy it, you can go pro for $15 a month and you can use the code CRIN to get your first
month of pro for only $3. If this sounds good, head over to go.warp.dev slash CRIN and check it
out for yourself. The link is also at the top of the description in the pinned comment. That's
pretty much it for people that want to get into programming but don't really care about jobs.
Now when it comes to getting a job in programming, here's what you need to do. First of all,
get a university degree because it's very useful and the competition will only get higher over time
and you're gonna need it. On top of everything that I'm about to say, obviously. If you're
more info on that, I also made a whole video on it. Okay, so another thing to finish the basics
is time to pick a field to specialize in and start working on more advanced projects. The reason
why I want to specialize on a specific field is because they vary quite a lot in the technologies
that they use and the skills that you need. So low level engineering is probably gonna need to know
sea, memory management, work closely with hardware, understand low level performance, optimization,
concurrency, be really good at operating systems and many other things of that sort. Meanwhile,
a web developer does the exact opposite and is gonna work with a high level language,
probably using Python and JavaScript and they don't really care about hardware or memory and they
don't have to optimize it in that way. Instead, they're gonna care more about APIs, web protocols,
data modeling, optimizations for servers and scaling, networking, device compatibility and
those sorts of things. That's pretty much it for the generic guide and you're not supposed to
get too much guidance because you're supposed to find your own path and think for yourself rather
than find a roadmap that's gonna work for everybody because it's probably not gonna work for everybody.
One more tip though is that if you wanna start with low level you need to understand data
structures and CS and low level concepts very well before you start working with that language
because otherwise there's no reason to use it and in general a developer needs to be very good at
CS principles and making stuff properly and well optimized. Other than that you just continue with
the project learning method and you find something that you find interesting and you wanna work on
and then you learn along the way even if it's very complicated and you don't know where to start.
For things that are kind of subfields on their own like AI for example you can just take courses
on it and then continue rather than just starting from scratch. Now I'm just going for some guidelines
that you need to follow as a programmer. Regardless of how complex the project is you should still
attempt it if it's a project that you wanna do and you'll just learn along the way. You shouldn't
be scared by the complexity. Don't just use the technology because you're comfortable with it when
there's much better alternatives. Like it's a very bad idea to parse a JSON by using strings and
then splitting the string instead of just using JSON parsing and when it comes to AI once you're
already learned basic syntax don't overuse it too much for problem solving or you're gonna become
a useless programmer. Also tutorial hell isn't a real thing you can just alternate between projects
and tutorials and find whichever balance you like. I personally watched about half an hour of tutorials
when I got started and then I got bored and I started doing projects. When it comes to projects
get creative and do stuff for the things that you actually use or enjoy. Yeah you could make macros
automation cheats or plugins or mods for the games or apps that you enjoy or you can even do
something a lot more abstract like an encryption app for discord. You'd have a password that would
generate an encryption key. You would share the password with your friend and then you would both
have the same encryption and the encryption key and from that you can just type in an encrypted
way through any communication app. All you really have to do is just get creative and do stuff for
the things you like. What I'm trying to tell you is you have so many options when you're looking at
projects that you can make and all you have to do is get creative and not be scared to just hop in
and try to do it. From now on it just comes down to you putting in the work and try to have fun.
In the beginning it's quite important that you have fun or you're gonna get bored and you're
gonna drop it very early and there's just no reason to make a fun experience miserable and other
than that. See you in the next one.